islamicboard.com 2019-12-12

# IslamicBoard - Discover Islam | Connect with Muslims - Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy**

Your privacy is of the utmost importance to Islamic Board. Because we ask for some basic personal information during registration, we want you to be fully informed of how this information is gathered and used. 

**Registration**

Some basic personal information is required in order to register with Islamic Board:   
• Email Address – By providing your email address, you can receive important messages via your existing email account. Message board notifications and notification of messages sent to you by other Islamic Board members rely on the email address you provide when you register.   
• User Name – This is how you are identified when you participate in forums. While many other aspects of your account can be updated regularly, your user name can only be changed by sending a request to an administrator.  
• Gender – Islamic ethics require us to maintain dignity while interacting with members of the opposite gender and forbids free-mingling and flirting.  
• Religion – This helps us to understand your point of view and know where you are coming from.

**Information Islamic Board Requests**

When you register, you are asked to give demographic information (like birth year, occupation, and location). We ask you to tell us a little about yourself so we can better understand the types of people who register. This information can also be used to provide you with content that may be of interest to you, and to show you advertisements that are relevant to your demographic information. Islamic Board uses outside ad companies to display ads on its sites. These ads may contain cookies. While Islamic Board uses cookies in other parts of its sites, the ad companies also use cookies with the ads displayed, and Islamic Board may not have access to this information. 

**Participation**

The above describes information that is provided "actively" - meaning, you choose to submit this information to us when you join Islamic Board, or update your account at any point after having joined. Some other information is provided "passively" - meaning, that Islamic Board obtains this information when you login to your Islamic Board account and use the service. This is done primarily through the use of "cookies." Cookies are used on Islamic Board to verify your login information, and to optionally store your password in your browser so that you do not need to type it in each time you visit. Any time that you point your browser to a 'members-only' area, Islamic Board checks your browser's cookie file to see if you have already logged in, and if you have, you're taken right to the page that you have requested. If not, you'll be directed to the Islamic Board login screen, where you can quickly and easily login to your account, or signup for Islamic Board if you are not yet a member. Cookies are also used in conjunction with some ad banners to determine their effectiveness. 

**Cookies**

Islamic Board uses cookies to customize your experience while using our services. A cookie is a small text file that many Web sites write through your browser when you visit them. A cookie can only be read by the site that places it, so Islamic Board can't learn about your browsing history based on any other cookies in your browser. Most browsers also allow the option of displaying a warning before accepting a cookie, or refusing all cookies. Declining cookies while participating in forums may result in some of features not working properly.

**Advertising**

Islamic Board uses third-party advertising companies and advertising networks to serve ads to you on our behalf when you visit our Web site. These companies may use information about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. Personally identifiable information such as your name, address, email address or telephone number are not shared with advertisers without your permission.   
Among the third-party advertising companies that Islamic Board uses is Google Adsense. For more information on their privacy policies, please consult the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/index.html).

**Public Forums**

Please remember that any information that is disclosed in public forums becomes public information. In addition, there is no guarantee that other forum participants will not disclose your information which you have shared in private forums, even if they have said they will keep it private as a condition of entry to the private forum. You should therefore exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

**Security**

Islamic Board has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under its control. Islamic Board's servers have strict security in place to prevent an intruder from retrieving personal information about its users. 

**Termination**

You can elect to terminate your membership with Islamic Board at any time. Simply post a request for account termination in the Helpdesk or contact an administrator. Upon termination, your account information and the contents posted by you will not necessarily be removed entirely from Islamic Board - this is to reserve your identity so that no one else can create a new account with your username or email address, and also allows you the privilege of reactivating your account at a later date if you wish to use Islamic Board again. The termination of your Islamic Board membership will not automatically terminate any affiliated memberships or registrations you have formed through Islamic Board. 

**Summary**

In this electronic era, when personal information can easily be obtained through various sources, Islamic Board appreciates the sensitivity of any private information that you disclose to us. It is our intention to treat your account information with the highest level of care. 

* * *
